一个经过良好测试的程序将进行测试
A well-tested program will have tests
对于程序中的每个模块，
for every individual module in the program,
其中模块可能是方法，也可能是类。
where a module might be a method or it might be a class.
单独测试单个模块的测试
A test that tests an individual module in isolation
称为单元测试。
is called a unit test.
单独测试模块会让您更轻松
Testing modules in isolation gives you a much easier time
调试。
of debugging.
因为当一个模块的单元测试失败时，
Because when a unit test for a module fails,
你可以确信
you can be confident that the bug
在那个模块中，而不是程序中的其他地方。
is in that module, rather than somewhere else in the program.
单元测试的对偶
The dual counterpart of a unit test
是一个集成测试，不仅仅是
is an integration test, which just doesn't just
测试一个模块——它实际上测试模块的组合
test one module-- it actually tests a combination of modules
甚至可能是整个计划。
or even perhaps the entire program.
现在如果你只有集成测试——嗯，
Now if all you have are integration tests-- well,
首先，这总比什么都没有好。
first of all, that's better than nothing.
但是只有集成测试的问题
But the problem of having only integration tests
或者只有整个程序测试是当一个测试失败时，
or only entire program tests is that when a test fails,
你得去找虫子。
you have to hunt for the bug.
你在整个程序中都在寻找
And you're stuck looking through the entire program for where
它失败了。
it failed.
集成测试仍然非常重要。
An integration test is still really important.
除了单元测试之外，你还想拥有它们，
You want to have them in addition to unit test,
因为程序在连接时可能会失败
because a program can fail at the connections
模块之间。
between modules.
在一个模块工作的一个编码器可能会做出假设
One coder working at one module may make assumptions
关于另一个模块
about another module that they're
使用那是不正确的。
using that aren't correct.
所以你仍然需要那些集成测试。
So you'd still need those integration tests.
但是如果你也有一套完整的单元测试
But if you also have a thorough set of unit tests
让你对正确性充满信心
that give you that confidence in the correctness
在各个模块中
of the individual modules, then you'll
当
have a lot less searching to do when
你得找个虫子——因为你会
you have to look for a bug-- because you'll
如果单元测试失败，它们将
have unit tests that are failing and they'll
说这里可能有个虫子。
say that there's probably a bug here.
这里有一个例子。
So here's an example.
假设你正在建立一个网络搜索引擎。
Suppose you're building a web search engine.
可能是两个低级模块
Maybe two of the low level modules
你得到的网页
that you've got are get web page which
获取一个URL并下载它并返回
takes a URL and downloads it and returns
其内容为字符串。
its contents as a string.
另一个模块可能需要一个字符串
Another module might take a string
它是由get web page生成的，比方说，
that was produced by get web page, let's say,
从中提取单词。
and extract the words from it.
因此，找出单词是相邻的所有单词
So find all the words where word is a contiguous
非空白字符和非虚字符的序列。
sequence of nonwhite space and nonpunctuation characters.
这个例子的细节并不重要，
The details of that doesn't really matter for this example,
但它将它们作为字符串列表返回。
but it returns them as a list of strings.
所以我们有这两个模块
So we've got these two modules, and they're
打算一起工作。
intended to work together.
事实上，我们还有一个更高级的模块
And in fact, we have another higher level module that
实际上两者都在使用。
is actually using them both.
所以它叫“让网页转动”
So it's calling get web page to turn
字符串中包含
a URL into the string that contains
网页的内容。
the contents of the web page.
然后调用字符串上的提取单词，
And then it's calling extract words on that string,
以便从网页中提取单词。
in order to get the words out of the web page.
如果我们写一个测试套件
Now if we were writing a test suite
对于这个包含三个模块的简单程序，
for this simple program with three modules in it,
这是我们想要的。
here's what we would want.
我们希望得到的网页单元测试
We would want unit tests for get web page that
确保它在不同的url上正常工作。
make sure it works correctly on various URLs.
我们希望单元测试只针对
We would want unit tests just for extract words that
在不同的弦上测试，有些甚至
tested on various strings, some which might not even
成为网页——因为你注意到
be web pages-- because you notice that extract words
它本身并没有说明这个东西是否
itself doesn't say anything about whether the thing is
网页。
a web page.
只是一根绳子。
It's just a string.
然后对make索引进行单元测试
And then unit test for make index
在不同的url集上测试的
that tested on various sets of URLs
看看它是否构造了这个索引
to see whether it constructs this index that it's
应该能正常返回。
supposed to return properly.
程序员有时会犯一个错误
Now one mistake that programmers sometimes
当你为某个东西编写单元测试时
make when you're writing unit tests for something
比如提取单词，在get网页的下游，
like extract words, which is downstream of get web page,
他们是以这样的方式编写这些测试用例的
is that they write those test cases in such a way
他们依赖于网页的正确性。
that they depend on get web page to be correct.
换句话说，当构造
In other words, when constructing
用于提取单词的输入，它们是
an input for extract words, they're
调用get web page以获取
calling get web page to get a web page that they
可以通过提取单词。
can pass to extract words.
这不是个好办法。
That's not a great approach.
原因是这取决于
The reason is that it's depending
论作为单元一部分的网页获取的正确性
on the correctness of get web page as part of the unit
测试提取单词。
test for extract words.
如果get web page中有错误，
If there's a bug in get web page,
它可能会在提取单词时错误地失败，
it might falsely fail on extract words,
即使抽取的单词没有那个缺陷。
even if extract words doesn't have that bug.
最好考虑并测试抽取的单词
It's much better to think about and test extract words really
隔离，并划分其输入空间
in isolation, and partition its input space
不太注意发生了什么
without paying much attention to what's happening
在程序的其余部分。
in the rest of the program.
使用分区和改进web页面可能是有意义的
It might make sense to use partitions and evolve web page
内容，因为这就是你实际使用它的方式。
content, because that's how you actually are going to use it.
但不要从那个测试用例调用get web page，
But don't call get web page from that test case,
因为获取网页可能有问题。
because get web page might be buggy.
相反，您应该存储该网页内容
Instead, you should store that web page content
作为测试用例中的文本字符串，
as a literal string in your test case,
直接传出来提取单词。
and pass it directly to extract words.
这样你就编写了一个独立的单元测试。
So that way you're writing an isolated unit test.
如果失败了，你可以自信
And if it fails, you can be confident
窃听器实际上是在提取单词，
that the bug is actually in extract words,
而不是在获取网页中
rather than maybe in get web page
也许是在摘录文字。
and maybe in extract words.
现在对于更高级别的单元测试——对于这个，使索引
Now for the higher level unit test-- for this make index that
同时使用get web page和extract words--
uses both get web page and extract words--
这样就很难把它隔离开来。
it's harder to isolate it that way.
当您为此调用make index到单元测试用例中时，
When you call make index into unit test case for that,
你实际上是在测试正确性
you're actually testing the correctness
不仅是make index中的代码，还包括
of not only the code in make index, but also the methods it
电话。
calls.
如果测试失败，它可能在这三个测试中的任何一个中
If the test fails, it might be in any one of these three
地方。
places.
所以我们需要一套好的独立测试
So that's why we actually want a good set of separate tests
为了增加我们的信心
for these to increase our confidence that those two
低级模块工作正常。
low level modules work correctly.
如果一个测试在make索引处失败了——好吧，
Then if a test fails up at make index-- well,
那么问题可能是make index中的代码
then the problem is probably the code in make index
那就是把这两个模块连接在一起。
that is connecting those two modules together.
可以隔离更高级别的模块，如make
It is possible to isolate the higher level module like make
索引如果我们写的是所谓的存根版本
index if we write what are called stub versions
它调用的模块。
of the modules that it calls.
例如，get web page的存根
So for example, a stub for get web page
可能根本无法上网，
might not even access the internet at all,
但是返回一个模拟网页
but instead return a mock web page
内容，不管传递给它的是什么URL，
content, no matter what URL was passed to it,
只是一个肯定的回答。
just a canned answer.
整个类的存根通常称为模拟对象。
A stub for a whole class is often called a mock object.
你可以在维基百科上了解更多。
You can learn more about that on Wikipedia.
当
Stubs are a really important technique when
你在建造大型系统。
you're building large systems.
你可能不会用这种小方法来做。
You probably wouldn't do them for small methods like this.
我们一般不会在课堂上使用它们。
And we're generally not going to use them in this class.